<AdditionalSkills>
  <Overview>
    These are skills that are not part of the core purpose of the course, but developing them would be useful.
  </Overview>

  <SkillsCategory>
    <Name>Python</Name>

    <Overview>
      The specific Python skills needed for this module are largely dictated by the project chosen. Creative projects might require image processing libraries, audio libraries, or specialized frameworks. Open-source LLM projects will require deep familiarity with ML libraries and model deployment.
    </Overview>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Machine Learning Libraries (PyTorch/TensorFlow)</SkillName>
      <Importance>Essential</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Deep understanding of PyTorch or TensorFlow for working with open-source models. Essential for model loading, inference, and potential fine-tuning.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Model Deployment &amp; MLOps</SkillName>
      <Importance>Essential</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Skills in deploying models to production-like environments. Understanding Docker, model serving frameworks, and resource management. Critical for open-source LLM projects.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Computer Vision Libraries (PIL, OpenCV)</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        For teams working with image generation or manipulation. Understanding image processing pipelines, transformations, and integration with diffusion models.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Audio Processing Libraries</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        For teams exploring AI music generation or voice synthesis. Libraries like librosa, pydub, or specialized audio AI frameworks.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Performance Optimization</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Profiling and optimizing Python code, especially for ML workloads. Understanding memory management, quantization, and acceleration techniques.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Environments &amp; Package Management</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Advanced dependency management for complex AI projects with many libraries. Handling version conflicts and ensuring reproducibility.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>
  </SkillsCategory>

  <SkillsCategory>
    <Name>System Administration &amp; DevOps</Name>

    <Overview>
      Working with open-source models often requires significant system administration skills, particularly for managing computational resources and deployment environments.
    </Overview>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>GPU Configuration &amp; Management</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Understanding CUDA, GPU drivers, and managing GPU resources. Essential for teams running models locally or on cloud instances.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Container Technologies (Docker)</SkillName>
      <Importance>Recommended</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Containerizing AI applications for consistent deployment. Particularly useful for packaging open-source model deployments.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>

    <Skill>
      <SkillName>Cloud Platform Management</SkillName>
      <Importance>Stretch</Importance>

      <SkillDescription>
        Using cloud platforms (AWS, GCP, Azure) for GPU instances and model hosting. Understanding free tiers and cost management.
      </SkillDescription>
    </Skill>
  </SkillsCategory>
</AdditionalSkills>
