<ResearchTopics>
  <Overview>
    These are topics that might be useful foci for the initial research session at the beginning of the module.
  </Overview>

	<PrimaryTopics>
    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>RAG Concepts and Case Studies</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Understanding RAG fundamentals
          - Find explanations of why RAG is useful and how companies use it
          - Examples: how Bing Search or enterprise chatbots use retrieval to give up-to-date info
          - RAG "combines LLMs with external knowledge to get more accurate, up-to-date answers"
        2. Real-world applications
          - Research case studies of successful RAG implementations
          - Understand the problems RAG solves vs. other approaches
          - Compare RAG to fine-tuning and when to use each
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Vector Databases</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Vector database options
          - Research at least one or two vector DB options
          - Consider Chroma (open source and easy to run)
          - Experiment with Pinecone's free tier or other cloud options
          - Weaviate, Qdrant, Milvus as alternatives
        2. Indexing and querying
          - How to index data in a vector database
          - How to perform similarity searches
          - Possibly demonstrate a tiny example (e.g. indexing 5 sentences and querying one)
        3. Trade-offs and considerations
          - Local vs. cloud-hosted solutions
          - Performance characteristics
          - Cost implications
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Embedding Models</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Embedding model selection
          - Research what embedding model to use for text
          - OpenAI's text-embedding-ada-002 is a straightforward choice via API
          - Local embedding models as alternatives (SBERT, InstructorXL)
        2. Trade-offs
          - OpenAI's embeddings are high-quality but cost per call
          - Local models might be free but less performant
          - Dimensionality considerations
        3. How semantic similarity works
          - Understand the concept of embedding space
          - How cosine similarity and other distance metrics work
          - How to choose appropriate similarity thresholds
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Prompting for QA with Context</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Prompt formatting strategies
          - How to format the prompt when you have retrieved documents
          - Strategies like "Answer the question using only the following context…"
          - Instructing the model to say if it doesn't know or if info wasn't found
        2. Citation and source referencing
          - How to ask the LLM to provide the source
          - Prompt templates that explicitly say: "Include a reference to the document in your answer"
          - Find community prompts or literature on this
        3. Handling context limitations
          - How much context to include in the prompt
          - Strategies for when retrieved documents exceed token limits
          - Balancing relevance vs. comprehensiveness
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Evaluation of RAG Systems</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Evaluation approaches
          - How to evaluate the chatbot's answers for factual accuracy
          - Creating an evaluation set with known answers
          - Unit tests for the chatbot
        2. Metrics for RAG
          - Precision and recall of retrieval
          - Groundedness of responses
          - Answer relevance and correctness
          - Using AI evaluators to measure quality
        3. Systematic testing
          - Awareness of how to systematically test an AI QA system
          - Industry practices for RAG evaluation
          - Identifying and handling failure modes
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>AI Agents and Function Calling</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. OpenAI Function Calling
          - Understand OpenAI's function calling feature in the Chat API
          - How developers specify functions (with name and parameters)
          - How the model decides to output a JSON to call them
          - Best practices to get reliable function calls
        2. Agent Frameworks
          - Explore libraries like LangChain agents or Microsoft's Semantic Kernel
          - What do these frameworks provide?
          - How agents implement reasoning loops (often using the ReAct framework)
          - Simple agent examples from documentation
        3. Case Studies of Autonomous Agents
          - Research experiments like AutoGPT or BabyAGI
          - What kinds of tasks were they able to automate?
          - Challenges encountered (getting stuck in loops, irrelevant actions)
          - Metrics or anecdotes on effectiveness and efficiency
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Tool Design and Safety for AI Agents</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Designing Tool APIs
          - How to choose and design tools for AI agents
          - Common tools: calculator, web search, knowledge lookup
          - Model-Compute-Pipeline (MCP) standard for connecting LLMs to tools
          - Error handling: what if the tool returns nothing useful?
        2. Ensuring Safe and Relevant Actions
          - How to keep the agent from doing unwanted things
          - Constraining the tools available
          - Strategies to keep the agent on track
          - Requiring the agent to explain why it's calling a function
          - Time-outs if too many steps
        3. Ethical boundaries
          - Privacy considerations when hooking to external APIs
          - Data security and access controls
          - Audit trails for agent actions
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>

    <PrimaryTopic>
      <TopicName>Multi-Agent Systems</TopicName>

      <TopicDescription>
        1. Advanced multi-agent frameworks
          - Research AutoGen, CrewAI, and similar frameworks
          - How these frameworks enable agent collaboration
          - Communication protocols between agents
        2. Agent coordination patterns
          - Task decomposition strategies
          - Consensus mechanisms in AI systems
          - Agent orchestration approaches
        3. Emergent behaviors
          - How distributed problem-solving works
          - Emergent intelligence in agent collectives
          - Mixture of experts approaches
          - Agent negotiation and debate patterns
      </TopicDescription>
    </PrimaryTopic>
  </PrimaryTopics>

	<StretchTopics>
	  <StretchTopic>Multi-turn and Memory in Agents: How agents carry state and manage results from previous function calls</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Graph databases for knowledge representation in RAG systems</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Hybrid search strategies combining vector and keyword search</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Fine-tuning embedding models for domain-specific applications</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Advanced chunking strategies and their impact on retrieval quality</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Agent memory architectures and long-term context management</StretchTopic>
		<StretchTopic>Verification and validation in multi-agent systems</StretchTopic>
	</StretchTopics>
</ResearchTopics>
