<research-topics>
	<primary-topics>
   	<primary-topic-1>
      Name:
      1.
    </primary-topic-1>
  </primary-topics>

	<stretch-topics>
    1.
	</stretch-topics>
</research-topics>

<research-topics>
		<primary>
				- New model domains
						|- Each group researches the domain of their interest: e.g. “How do text-to-image models work and what libraries can we use easily?”, “What are good free resources for AI music generation?”, or “Are there APIs for X?” They likely will find tools like the Diffusion Web UIs, or pre-trained models on Hugging Face, etc.
				- Ethical and Social Implications
						|- Each team identifies if their project has any controversial aspects. As a class, we might list these out: e.g. “AI art and artist rights”, “AI in creative writing – originality concerns”, “Deepfakes and trust”, “AI humor and offense”. They research the debates around their topic. For instance, one group might present on the lawsuits around AI art datasets and another on instances where an AI chatbot said inappropriate things and why content filters matter. This covers the requirement (a) to robustly acknowledge debates and ensures everyone is aware of pitfalls.
				- Toolkits and Frameworks
						|- Groups will find what technical tools help their project. E.g., one group might demo using the Stable Diffusion API or local install, another might show how to use a particular Python library for MIDI generation. This exchange during the research share can spark cross-pollination of ideas (maybe the music group finds a tip from the art group’s research, etc.).
				- Stretching AI capabilities
						|- Possibly research how far they can push the models – e.g., can we fine-tune a small model on our own images (like making a Stable Diffusion model generate images of our group)? That might require Colab and some knowledge of fine-tuning steps. Even if not executed, learning about it is valuable.
		</primary>

		<stretch>
		</stretch>
</research-topics>

<inbox>
		- Adaptive AI systems & reinforcement learning basics
		- A/B testing for AI features
		- Prompt optimization techniques
		- User modeling & personalisation
		- Evaluation metrics for generative AI
		- Building feedback loops
		- Adaptation
		- evaluation
		- continuous improvement
</inbox>
